Nark?!
No, it's not!
Let's bring it down!
I finally managed to catch it.
What is that thing?
Oscar brought it back from a ruins expedition.
He told me it was a stone egg,
but it must have hatched at some point.
Great work reformulating
a suitable spell so quickly.
Or perhaps it's only natural
for our new chief mage...
Valt.
I'm honored, Your Majesty.
~ Once upon a Time with You ~
How many cycles have I lived now?
I've never tried counting.
However, this is the first time
I've joined the Farsas royal court.
I swear!
Bringing back such a suspicious item!
Spirit sorcerer ruins
are full of dangerous things!
Okay, I get it.
I can tell you don't from that reply!
It was likely used for patrolling.
Yes.
However, it contains
an unfamiliar spell composition.
I'll set about analyzing it.
Thanks.
So, how did the towns to the east look?
You mean the increase in sudden deaths
and suicides of unknown cause?
Quite frankly,
the investigation's not going well.
Even those who escape death end up
losing their sanity or falling into a coma.
I see.
Many of the casualties are mages,
with their magic going haywire,
but the postmortems don't tell us much
about their condition.
Tinasha.
The barrier around the castle city
doesn't allow demons to pass, does it?
That's correct.
Though it won't do much
against the highest-ranking ones.
Then can you set up the same barrier
around the towns and villages to the east?
Yes, but not all at once.
Whatever you can manage is fine.
Five days before the first unnatural death...
At Minnedart Fortress,
which guards the eastern border,
a mage fell from a rampart to his death.
If we assume it was the same cause of death...
It'd mean whatever's causing the deaths
is approaching us from the east.
What I've learned from living countless lives
is the fact that things you have
no knowledge of occur all the time.
I knew nothing of the king bringing back
a mysterious egg from the ruins,
nor of the outbreak
of suspicious deaths within Farsas.
Last month, there was an expedition
from Minnedart Fortress
to subdue the Ito, an equestrian tribe.
That was also new to me.
It'd be best to write it
all down in the records...
The records, huh?
Could this all be meaningless?
Valt. The food's ready.
I'll be right there.
Anything interesting
happen lately in the castle?
I go there to do work, you know.
I saw a stone bird flying around the palace.
Made of stone?!
How does it fly?
In the Dark Age, people did research
on similar magical creatures.
The queen is going to analyze it,
so I'll ask her to show me the spell diagram.
You sound so enthusiastic
whenever you talk about magic.
I wish I'd been born with magic, too.
I'm lending you my magic, aren't I?
That's nothing but a mark.
It's not like I can use magic with it.
On that note, strange deaths have been
cropping up recently east of here.
His Majesty thinks
it might be the work of demons.
Make sure you keep an eye out.
Sure.
But it's not like I ever leave the castle city.
I have no reason to.
Just making sure.
Which one of us do you need?
Her Majesty.
There's a merchant caravan
with a demonic beast in tow,
asking for an inspection
to enter the castle city.
If you would grant me the authority,
I can handle it for you.
Ask Valt to deal with it.
With how weary you are,
it'll be a while until you're fit to be seen.
Please do, then.
As you wish.
Are those the same birds?
They're smaller now.
Fascinating, right?
I made copies of them following my analysis.
It seems they were created to patrol after all,
but they're equipped with
a spraying mechanism, too.
Spraying?
It looks like it wants to come along.
Valt?
Miralys.
What's with the flowers?
They're for decoration back home.
Don't you think that's an awful lot?
At the shop I always go to, they had
a customer back out of an order.
I bought all the flowers
to help their predicament.
Miralys, you're a kind girl.
That's not true at all...
Say, what's that on your shoulder?
This is a magical creature made by Her Majesty.
Can I pet it later?
Go right ahead.
Huh? What's wrong?
I'm not sure, but...
I think...
That's Tris and...
Savas    Prince of Yarda
the Yarda prince, Savas?
Why are they here?
Go on.
Miralys!
Miralys...
Feast your eyes on this, Leonora!
This spells the end for that witch!
I thought I'd understood.
The fact that things I have
no knowledge of occur all the time.
She will never open her eyes again.
There's no trace left of her soul.
The world waits for its chance.
Which is why, at times,
it can catch up to her like this.
As though to say, "This is as far as you go."
That which robs mages of their sanity,
forces their magic to go haywire,
and devastates their spirits and lives.
Irityrdia, the sole god of Tayiri,
was what had been sealed inside Tris.
You know of it?
Irityrdia, freed last month in
the aftermath of the fight against the Ito,
had been slowly making its way
while causing death around it,
until it was captured in its path.
Savas must have been
after Tinasha from the very start.
An act of vengeance for killing Leonora,
the witch he had worshiped?
The stone birds were spraying
a psychological safeguard against Irityrdia.
It's thanks to them that you're still sane
after you came in close contact
with that thing.
Three hundred dead in three days' time.
To contain Irityrdia,
which had been growing stronger,
our only choice was to destroy it
with Akashia while Tinasha was its vessel.
She was the one who was
the most careless with her own life.
So in exchange, I wanted to treat it
with more care than anyone else.
I'm certain Queen Tinasha
understood that the best.
The blame lies with me
for being unable to prevent this.
I'm sorry for making you go through this.
Here's to your health and prosperity.
Until we meet in another time,
in another manner.
Yeah. You too.
If you could turn back time
and redo everything,
what do you think you'd do?
I'm afraid I can't say.
But I do know...
That if it was for my own sake,
I wouldn't be able to go through with it.
The you here is a different you from before.
That's a thought I couldn't help but entertain.
But you are you.
The world will not diverge.
Throughout every cycle,
your soul is unique to you.
Which is why I'm going to go see you again...
Miralys.
Valt?
You were sleeping out here?
Good morning.
You must be tired, dozing off like that.
I'm fine.
I was just dreaming about the past.
Events from the distant past,
which no longer exist at all.
Precious memories that remain nowhere else.
What's up?
Huh? Oscar?
I got lost in thought concentrating.
My apologies.
What were you thinking about?
Your brows were furrowed.
This and that.
Oscar, do you know the tale of
the Mirror of Oblivion?
Yeah, I think it's about a mirror
that takes all your sadness away.
Mirror of Oblivion
It's an old fairy tale
dating back to the early Dark Age.
But in some regions, it takes away
your memories instead of sadness,
or makes you fall asleep
after absorbing your spirit.
It changes a little each time.
Huh, interesting.
And tracing all the accounts, the last place
the mirror is said to have been seen is...
Magdalsia, huh?
You think that fairy tale has something
to do with the witch in Magdalsia?
If all the Witch of the Forbidden Forest
wanted was to control the nation,
it'd be easier to control the king's mind
instead of putting him into a coma.
You mean the witch appeared
because the king fell ill?
Or so I suspect.
What caused the mysterious coma
and summoned the witch?
Tinasha?
I think I'll go see what's
happening in Magdalsia after all.
What?
Not a chance.
There's no need for you to meddle.
I'm the only human who can fight
the Witch of the Forbidden Forest.
Even so...
She wields the royal authority of Magdalsia.
With your standing, you could
very well end up causing a war.
You'll send us back to the Dark Age.
I'm sure things will work themselves out.
Tinasha!
You have no right to stop me.
Didn't you travel
four hundred years to be with me?
The two of us would be enemies
if not for the times we live in.
I don't know what goes on in your head.
There were quite a few heads
of our family before me.
These are the records of
the countless fragments of their lives.
Have you ever written these, too?
A number of times.
The events that came to pass,
what changed between different cycles...
If there's anything I want
to tell those who succeed me,
writing this is the only way.
There's no need to look so grim.
The people who wrote this down
did so of their own volition.
There are records of the Witch
of the Azure Moon in here, right?
Yes, there are.
That said, she very rarely
came down from her tower.
I'd say I know more than what's
been documented here.
Since I know her from when she was queen...
Wh-What?!
Don't tell me...
She ignored Magdalsia and came here instead?!
Miralys, this way!
If you think I'd fail to act,
you're sorely mistaken.
Valt?!
It's fine.
I can't have these remain.
Is this the side of her
I don't know, as a Dark Age ruler?
Not bad.
He's put up a pretty strong barrier.
Time to penetrate it.
A girl?
Writings?
Sorry, Lady Tinasha.
They got away.
Lady Tinasha?
He ticks me off.
Looks like Queen Tinasha's not here yet.
She seems pretty busy lately.
At least she gave up
on taking action all by herself.
Here she is.
Didn't bother to dress up, I see.
Not to mention you're late.
I barely made it.
I haven't eaten since this morning, either...
Today hasn't been a good day.
Here, something sugary.
Starting off with dessert?!
Why'd you call me over?
Something troubling has come to light.
Let's get right to the point.
Do you have memories of time repeating?
Oh, is that all?
Nope, no memories.
Since those orbs are outsiders' artifacts.
Outsiders' artifacts?
What? Never heard of them?
In simple terms, it refers to all artifacts
with powers that defy the laws of magic.
I'm susceptible to their effects, too.
Are you really?
You behave strangely at times.
Like you know what the future holds,
or you've experienced it.
I really don't know! Lay off it.
Travis, I saw records of a history
that no longer exists.
Before history changed, Cezar thrived
as a wealthy Great Nation,
and it never invaded Farsas.
You saw all that?
Aurelia, go run off and play.
What? I can't...
Off you go.
Make sure you don't follow strangers.
Let me begin by saying that
I really don't have any memories.
However, I've come across records as well.
A family known as the Time-Readers:
they retain their memories
through repeated histories,
and these extensive memories
are written down and passed on.
The current family head is...
Valt.
Tell us more about them.
Why should I?
Valt is after Eleterria!
What?
Why are they called
"outsiders' artifacts," anyway?
I've never even heard the term before.
That's because their
very existence is problematic.
Not exactly the kind of thing
you can blabber on about.
We're talking about items introduced
from outside our world.
So there really does exist something out there?
Well, whether you believe it
or not is up to you.
Even if there are beings that get their kicks
from watching you humans from outside,
what's it matter, right?
Like how the characters in a book aren't
aware of the world outside the book?
It's futile to even try and
understand what they're thinking.
I met one of them a long time ago.
A completely unfathomable woman.
You met one of them?!
That's not fair!
It's like you were given all the answers!
Quiet!
It's your fault for being ignorant.
Besides, that woman was an outsider,
but also not really.
Choosing to align herself with humans,
she lived and died among them.
Long before you were ever born.
She was the only one of her kind,
and she's got nothing to do
with the outsiders' artifacts.
Are you talking about...
Your Majesty!
I have an urgent message!
Magdalsian soldiers have just crossed
the border and begun their invasion!
Their army is about thirty thousand men!
In half an hour, they'll make contact
with a Tuldarr village to the south!
What'd you say?
That was sooner than I'd expected.
I understand.
Please tell the troops to mobilize.
Right away!
I must leave now to attend to this matter.
Thank you for your time, Travis.
Magdalsia has chosen war, then.
She's finally back to her old self.
I was wondering when she'd grow a spine again.
Don't give me that look.
She's always been like that.
Following up on earlier...
Don't hand over Eleterria.
I'd rather not do everything over.
Don't use them or have them stolen.
I don't plan on giving up Aurelia,
or the rest of this history.
Change of plans.
I'm going back to Farsas.
Tinasha viewed herself
as foreign to this era all along.
Could it be that she never
intended to become my queen?
Who goes there?
Forgive the intrusion,
but I was hoping we could talk.
Valt...
~ At Memory's End ~